<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data EconoScientist</title><link>https://georgetsilva.github.io/</link><description>An economist's adventures in data science.</description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://georgetsilva.github.io/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 03:40:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Exploring Arlington's Bikeometer Data</title><link>https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/exploring-arlingtons-bikeometer-data/</link><dc:creator>George T. Silva</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;
&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arlington, Virginia has this great Bikeometer on the Custis Trail in Rosslyn. This tall digital sign always catches my attention when I ride by it. It displays the number of bicycles that pass that sign daily, monthly and year to date. I discovered that this data is also available online. I decided to use my Python skills to import this data, clean it up, and do some basic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/exploring-arlingtons-bikeometer-data/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/exploring-arlingtons-bikeometer-data/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 04:10:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About George T. Silva</title><link>https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/about-george-t-silva/</link><dc:creator>George T. Silva</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a resource economist with a passion for data analysis and
technology. Over the past few years, I've watch the development of the
data science field and I've become increasingly interested in the
subject. Data science seems to complement the tools economists use to
understand how humans allocate scarce resources. While econometrics
tries to fit data to economic models, data science can help fill in the
gaps between economic theories and may even help discover new economic
models. My goal is master these new techniques of data science and share
them with you here on this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be primarily working in the Python programming language. While
I've used R in the past, I've come to discover that the general
flexibility and scalability of Python will likely make it the dominate
platform for conducting data science. Therefore, I've spent the past
year learning Python. One of my favorite resources for getting up to
speed with Python has been the book, &lt;em&gt;Automate the Boring Stuff with
Python&lt;/em&gt; by Al Sweigart. After figuring out the basics of Python
programming, I've moved on to Pandas, Folium, Requests, Selenium,
Matplotlib, NLTK, Numpy, and Scikit-learn. It seems like I find a new
interesting Python libraries every week now. This is quite a shift from
my traditional economic toolset of Excel, SAS, SQL, and ArcGIS to get my
work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I hope to blend my background in economics with the new
techniques in data science to create some whole new methods for using
data to learn about the world. Maybe I'll become a Data EconoScientist
along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/about-george-t-silva/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 03:25:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><dc:creator>George T. Silva</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello world! This is my first post using &lt;strong&gt;Nikola&lt;/strong&gt;. I'll be sharing my data science discoveries using Jupyter Notebooks that display my Python code and results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking forward to exploring this relatively new field and applying it to my domain knowledge in resource economics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Nikola</category><guid>https://georgetsilva.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 03:54:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>